focusvision.com 2019-08-30

# Privacy Policy | FocusVision

Last updated: **September 26, 2018**

FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. and its global affiliates and subsidiaries, including Decipher, Kinesis Panel, and Revelation, collectively ( **“FVW”** ) take privacy seriously. This General Privacy Notice ( **“Notice”** ) explains who we are, how we collect, share and use personal information about you, and how you can exercise your privacy rights. This Notice only applies to personal information we collect in the usual course of business, including through our websites (such as [https://www.focusvision.com](https://www.focusvision.com/)) ( **“Website”** ) and in connection with our events, sales, and marketing activities.

Please read the FVW Privacy Statement to understand how your personal information will be treated by FVW and its affiliates and subsidiaries.

### Who we are

FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. is a company incorporated under the laws of the [State of Delaware, USA and whose principal office is located at 1266 East Main Street, Stamford, CT 06902 USA]. We provide research technology solutions, including live-stream focus groups and surveys for our customers. [Find out more](https://www.focusvision.com/company/about/).

### Collection of Your Personal Information

In order to schedule and access some FVW services, we may require personal information including your name, email address, mailing address and phone number. This information may be provided by you directly or another designated by you to schedule or complete a service. For example: When you log in to view a scheduled FVW transmission project or recording, you will be asked to supply us with your name, email address, phone number and company name. This information is referred to as your personal login information (PLI). Information we obtain during this login process is treated differently than personal information we obtain via other means as noted below. We may also collect information about your visits to our website, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken in connection with our site and services. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring Website addresses. When you receive newsletters or promotional email from FVW, we may use web beacons (described below), customized links or similar technologies to determine whether the email has been opened and which links you click in order to provide you more focused email communications or other information. On a case by case basis, FVW may also collect additional personal information, subject to the voluntary consent of the disclosure, including, but not limited to, likenesses, voices, race, ethnicity, gender, opinions and views on particular products and services from 3rd Parties. We may also supplement the information we collect with information obtained from other companies. For example, we may use services from other companies that enable us to associate your activity while on our website with your IP address in order to improve our site and services.

### Decipher Surveys by FocusVision:

FVW collects a wide range of information about survey respondents depending on the information needs of our clients requesting the surveys through its Decipher Platform. For example, survey respondents may be requested to provide certain personally identifiable, financial or demographic information, as well as specific opinions about a variety of goods and services. Responses to all survey questions are completely voluntary. A survey respondent should only provide responses to questions they are comfortable answering and survey respondents may decline to answer any survey question.

### Revelation by FocusVision:

FVW, through its Revelation Platform, may collect information from you at two different stages. First, we collect anonymous, aggregate information from all visitors to the site. This information is never linked to any personally identifiable information and is only used in the aggregate to generate statistical reports about the use of our site. Second, Revelation collects personally identifiable information from you on behalf of the researcher whose study you have participated in. Online account creation may require you to submit the following personal information: name, address, company information, email address, and phone number. Study creators may have their own privacy policies which apply to studies that they have created using our services and that detail how they handle your personally identifiable information. We encourage you to read any such policy. Your submission of personally identifiable information is voluntary and you may opt out of responding at any time. If you do respond, you consent to its provision to us for the purpose of delivering our services to the study creator and or their end-client.

### KinesisPanel by FocusVision:

FVW, through its Kinesis Panel, collects two kinds of information about users:

Data that users volunteer by signing up to receive news and product information, entering contests, completing surveys, or buying directly from us; and  
Aggregated tracking data we collect when users interact with us.  
FVW uses the personal information you provide voluntarily to Kinesis to senchild information you’ve requested. The specific use of your personal information varies, depending on how you contact us:

When you subscribe to Kinesis Platform mailing lists to receive Kinesis news and product information, you must provide an email address. We never sell or rent the email address you provide when subscribing to our lists.  
When you enter a contest or survey, we may ask for your name, address, and email address so we can administer the contest and notify winners  
Use of Your Personal Login Information (PLI)  
FVW collects and uses your personal login information, provided to us during the login process, solely to deliver the services you have requested, for security purposes and to provide you with important communications such as product improvements and technical service issues.

### Use of Your Personal Information other than PLI

We typically use the personal information we collect through our Website in the usual course of our business for the following reasons: (i) to respond to a request that you sent us, such as a request for information about our Services; (ii) to administer, protect, and improve our Website and our Services; (iii) to better understand the preferences of our Website visitors; (iv) to compile aggregated statistics about Website usage; (v) to provide you with marketing and promotional communications (where this is in accordance with your marketing preferences); and/or (vi) for other business purposes such as data analysis, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our marketing, and enhancing, customizing and improving our Websites, products and services.

### Sharing of Your Personal Login Information (PLI)

Except as described in this statement, we will not disclose your personal login information outside of FVW (or it’s subsidiaries) without your consent.

### Sharing of Your Personal Information other than PLI with Third Parties

We may disclose personal information that FVW and/or its subsidiaries collect or you provide:

To Clients of FVW who commission market research studies, tools, analysis and software platforms.  
To our subsidiaries and affiliates.  
To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business ( and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them).  
To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of FVW’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by FVW about our users is among the assets transferred.  
For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information, with your consent.  
To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.  
To protect and defend the rights or property of FVW (including the enforcement of our agreements).  
To act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of FVW services or members of the public. We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings or for research purposes. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose.

To any other person with your consent to the disclosure.

Please be aware that FVW may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

FVW is liable for inappropriate onward transfers of personal data to third parties.

### Links to Other Sites

Our Website may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by FocusVision. Please be aware that FocusVision is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and statements of other sites to understand their information practices. This Notice applies only to information collected by our Website.

### International Data Transfer

Please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country. Specifically, our servers are located in the United States, Europe, and Australia and our third party service providers (including Amazon Web Services (“AWS”)) and partners operate around the world. This means that when we collect your personal information we may process it in any of these countries.

We have implemented appropriate safeguards with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided upon request.

### Children under the Age of 13

FocusVision does not collect personal data from Minors or allow them to register for our surveys. Our services are not intended for and may not be used by minors. “Minors” are individuals under the age of 13 (or under a higher age if permitted by the laws of their residence). If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a Minor, we will delete that information and deletion will occur without notice. If you believe we might have any information from or about a Minor, please contact us at the address provided below.

### Accessing Your Personal Information

FVW recognizes the right of individuals to access their personal information. You have the ability to view or edit your personal information online. In order to help prevent your personal information from being viewed by others, you will be required to login with information provided by FVW.

### HR Data

FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship. With respect to any complaints relating to this Policy that cannot be resolved through FocusVision Worldwide, Inc.’s internal processes, FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. has agreed to cooperate with the European data protection authorities and to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European data protection authorities to resolve disputes pursuant to the Privacy Shield Principles. FocusVision is also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission, which is the competent supervisory authority under the Privacy Shield.

### Communication Preferences

You can stop the delivery of future promotional email from FVW sites and services by following the specific instructions in the email you receive. You may also have the option of proactively making choices about the communications you receive from FVW by emailing [privacy@focusvision.com](mailto:privacy@focusvision.com) with your preferences or contacting us at Privacy Officer, FocusVision WorldWide, Inc., 7 River Park Place East, Suite 110, Fresno, CA 93720, +1 (203) 428-2448.

### Security of Your Personal Information

We use appropriate administrative, organizational, technical and physical safeguards to protect the personal information we collect and process about you. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information and to help ensure that your data is safe, secure, and only available to you and to those you provided authorized access (e.g., your users). Specific measures we use include encryption through protocols such as Secure Socket Layer (SSL). However, no electronic transmission over the Internet or information storage technology can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, so you should take care in deciding what information you send us in this way. If a password is provided to help protect your projects and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential.

### Privacy Shield Policy

FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. and its US affiliates (Decipher, Inc; Kinesis Survey Technologies, LLC; and Revelation, Inc.) comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. and its US affiliates have certified to the Department of Commerce that they adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. For more information about the Privacy Shield, see the US Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield website located at: https://www.privacyshield.gov. To review our certification on the Privacy Shield list, see the US Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield self-certification list located at: https://www.privacyshield.gov/list.

The United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is the enforcement authority with jurisdiction over this compliance with the Privacy Shield.

In compliance with the US-EU and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. at:

Privacy Officer  
FocusVision Worldwide, Inc.  
7 River Park Place East Suite 110,  
Fresno, CA 93720  

FocusVision Worldwide, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacyshield/for-eu-consumers>

for more information and to file a complaint. Where a complaint cannot be resolved by any of the before mentioned recourse mechanisms, individuals may have a right to invoke binding arbitration under the Privacy Shield Panel as a recourse mechanism of ’last resort’.

Note, in certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### Data Retention

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements, to enforce our agreements or comply with our legal obligations).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

Please contact us at [privacy@focusvision.com](mailto:privacy@focusvision.com) if you have any questions about the information we collect and/or how we use the information we collect.

### Choice

FVW will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their Personal Information is (a) to be disclosed to a third party acting as a controller, or (b) to be used for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. For sensitive personal information, FVW will give individuals the opportunity to affirmatively and explicitly consent (opt-in) to the disclosure of their Sensitive Personal Information to (a) a third party acting as a controller or (b) the use of the information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. FVW will provide individuals with reasonable (especially clear and conspicuous, readily available) mechanisms to exercise their choices.

### Access

If you are an EU Person or a person from Switzerland about whom we hold personal Data on our own or client’s behalf, you may request access to, and the opportunity to update, correct or delete, such personal Data. To submit such requests or raise any other questions to our clients, please contact the business that provided your personal Data. You can also contact our EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Contact. We reserve the right to take appropriate steps to authenticate an applicant’s identity, to charge an adequate fee before providing access and to deny requests, except as required by the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

### Use of Cookies

FVW uses “cookies” to enable you to sign in to our services more easily and to help personalize your online experience. A “cookie” is a set of data that a web server stores on your computer that enables the server to recognize your computer. Cookies enable websites to “remember” your entries as you move from page to page, or when you revisit the site from time to time using the same computer. The data set that makes up a cookie will typically not have any meaning to anyone other than the party that placed the cookie. A cookie cannot retrieve other data from your computer’s hard drive or pass on computer viruses. Two different types of cookies are used in connection with our website: “Session cookies” track the user’s progression through our sites in a single visit. These cookies enable us to remember things as the user progresses from one page to another. With most Internet browsers, session cookies are either deleted or rendered inaccessible to us and our agents as soon as the user closes his or her browser. “Persistent cookies” allow us to remember a user at the user’s next visit. Persistent cookies are neither automatically erased nor rendered inaccessible upon closing the user’s browser, although persistent cookies will typically “expire” after some number of years. Upon expiration, such cookies may be deleted by the user’s browser or rendered inaccessible to us. (If you do not want these cookies to remain on your computer, you can erase them through use of your browser settings.) Both session and persistent cookies may also be used in connection with HTML email sent by us. Your browser or other software you install may permit you to restrict the use of session cookies, persistent cookies or all cookies. If you elect to not permit the use of persistent cookies only, you may enjoy the full functionality of our website; however, if you do so, you will need to re-enter some data upon your return visit or during the login process.

### Use of Web Beacons

FVW Web pages may contain electronic images known as “pixel tags”, “web beacons” or other technologies (collectively, “web beacons”). Web beacons are used to collect non-personally identifiable data and to assist in delivering cookies on our site and allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver services. We may include Web beacons in promotional email messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.

### Enforcement of This Privacy Statement

If you have questions regarding this statement, please contact us at: Privacy Officer, FocusVision WorldWide, Inc., 7 River Park Place East, Suite 110, Fresno, CA 93720, +1 (203) 355-9020, [privacy@focusvision.com](mailto:privacy@focusvision.com).

### Changes to This Privacy Statement

We will occasionally update this privacy statement to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this Statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of this statement. If there are material changes to how FVW will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We suggest you periodically review this statement to be informed of how FVW is protecting your information.

Subsidiaries and Affiliates of FVW, bound by this Privacy Policy include:

Decipher, Inc.  
Kinesis Survey Technologies, LLC  
Revelation, Inc.

Contacting Us  
FVW welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us at: Privacy Officer, FocusVision WorldWide, Inc., 7 River Park Place East, Suite 110, Fresno, CA 93720, +1 (203) 355-9020, [privacy@focusvision.com](mailto:privacy@focusvision.com).
